A lot of people have a fear of falling backwards.
We're going to show you how to do a roll, that will let you overcome that fear, so if you do fall on the ground, you won't hurt yourself in this manner.
Jason, I'm going to start the same way with the forward roll, one leg up, only this time obviously, we're going backwards, so whatever leg is up, everything is going to come to that side.
Everything is looking back to that side.
From here, all he's going to do is put that leg up, and plant it behind him, go ahead.
He plants whatever foot is up, turn around.
He kicks it up and he plants it behind him, finishing the roll, again.
He goes over the same shoulder, around, so whatever leg is up, he's going to go over this shoulder.
Making a nice tight ball, he's going to go from one shoulder to the other hip, again, good.
Ok, so the backwards roll is from standing, is if somebody comes to push you, or if they come to grab you, and there's something behind you and you trip and fall, so I'm going to demonstrate pushing on Jason and he's going to take a backwards fall from standing, here, boom.
See, as he rounds out his body, it makes a complete roll, and it doesn't really hurt any of his body parts.